[music]
>> Hello, hello. Fantastic to see you guys
here. I still can't believe they're
letting me take a stage at something
like this, a YouTuber apparently, but
can't wait to share a bit about how I've
been thinking because if I'm being real,
kind of going through some AI psychosis.
Who here would classify how they feel
right now as some form of AI psychosis?
I want to see some hands.
The Those who don't have their hands up
yet, don't worry. We'll get you there by
the end of this talk if I do everything
right.
In order to talk about this, I want to
start with a bit of a personal journey
of my own. And I'm going to go through
this the way anybody does in modern
timelines,
with the models.
Who here used Sonnet 3.5 when it was the
creme de la creme, the cream of the crop
model available to us?
It was unbelievably better than what we
had used before, right? Like having used
all of these different models and trying
them in tools, Sonnet 3.5 was a big
moment for me because it felt like these
models could suddenly complete much more
end-to-end tasks, like actually get real
work done that takes multiple steps.
And then we got Opus 4.5. Who felt or
I'll go a different way differently
here. Who didn't feel a big jump when
they switched over to Opus 4.5?
That's a relief. There were not too many
hands because Opus 4.5 is probably when
my psychosis started in November and
December of last year. Having a model
that couldn't just write the code and
call tools, but could go way further. A
model that could test the work and
actually get it into a good state and
complete tasks that take hours instead
of minutes. It was unbelievable.
And then we got Mythos.
Who here has had a chance to play with
Mythos and Fable so far?
We agree it's a pretty damn good model,
right?
But why? It's not just better at coding.
If you handed a prompt that you would
have handed to these other models
before, it's not going to feel that
different.
I think of these almost as eras now,
where Sonnet 3.5 is the tool call era.
Not that it was the first model that
could do tool calls, rather it was the
first one that did them consistently and
reliably enough in context of a code
base where you could use this for
day-to-day coding work.
Then we got Opus 4.5, which was able to
do much longer running tasks without
losing track of what it's working on.
It's no longer, "Okay, build step one."
and then it does it. Then you say,
"Okay, can you build this next part?"
and then the next part. You can just
tell it what you want, and it could
figure it out a lot of the time.
Mythos is another jump
to orchestration.
It feels to me like it's the first model
that doesn't just understand your code
base, but it understands itself. And it
knows how to spawn additional models and
break up work in a way where it could be
completed more reliably and then
verified afterwards. And if you tell the
model to do that, it will just do it.
You don't need some custom tooling, some
custom system, some fancy software
factory. You just need to prompt it to
go a little further. I think you'll be
surprised how far it can go.
What I'm trying to say here is we need
to go bigger.
You're not going to see the benefits
going forward if you're not pushing the
model further, you're not pushing
yourself further with what you're
building. Most of the Jira tickets I
closed in my previous job could be
trivially solved with a model like Opus
4.5.
My previous work would not benefit from
a model like Mythos.
If the models are going to keep getting
better, and at this point I'm confident
saying we they I was wrong when I
claimed that we were hitting a wall
before.
The models are getting better faster
than we are. So, we can't necessarily
get better. So, instead we have to go
bigger.
In order to do that, we have to get over
ourselves. This was really hard for me
as someone who spent a long time writing
software. Who here has written code for
more than 10 years? I want to see hands.
That's the majority of the people here.
I don't want to think about how long
I've been writing code for. But I have
been building up all of these strong
opinions since I started. I was using
GNU screen and eventually tmux back in
the day. I learned how to use those
tools and SSH and get before I even
wrote code. And those have all been
really ingrained in my workflow.
I think back to the old days in a weird
way. Hear me out. Let me talk about iOS
for a second.
Who owned an iPhone back when they
looked like this? iOS 6 or earlier?
How have you guys written code for 10
years when a fourth of you are that old?
I'm confused. Hopefully, you're all
Android people or something.
This is how iPhone apps used to look.
You might notice it's different from how
they look now. It looks less like an app
and more like somebody took a picture of
a compass and put it in the phone.
This is how apps used to look.
But, now they look like this.
And most people look at that and they're
like, "Oh, that's an obvious downgrade.
That's so much worse. Why would Apple
ever do that? This is the downfall of
Apple and the beauty of their design."
I'm going to fight you guys on that.
iOS 7 was Apple moving away from trying
to convince you that these devices can
replace the old tools we used to rely
on. The compass had to look like a
compass because the compass had to
replace the physical compass that you
relied on.
The books app had to look like a
bookshelf with real pages that turned
because I had to convince you it was a
reasonable alternative to buying a book
and reading the paper version.
Apps had to be designed to convince you
to use them, not to be useful.
And iOS 7 represents the shift to not
focusing on convincing you anymore.
Apple won. By that point, everyone knew
their iPhone could do all of these
different things. The point of iOS 7 was
to stop convincing and start embracing.
Start making a better interface. And
this interface, as much as we might not
like how it looks, it's so much more
useful. You have clear indications of
the difference between what direction
you're you're on and where you're
currently pointing. That red block is a
super nice way to know that you're not
in the direction you intend.
The current direction you're facing is
way clearer, too, with the giant 228 at
the bottom. You just get way more info
here than you did before. It's so much
clearer. Even if we don't like it
because it's not the thing we're used
to,
we got over it.
We're currently in our skeuomorphic
phase as software developers.
Skeuomorphism is this design aesthetic
trying to represent the way things used
to look, the physical goods that we
relied on, and try to make them digital.
We're doing this right now with
software.
We're pretending our terminals are the
ultimate interface when they're not even
good interfaces. And I'm saying this as
someone who loves their terminal deeply.
Natural language has no place in a
terminal, but we pretend it does because
the terminal's familiar. It's what we
It's what we're used to. It's what we
love. It's where we like to think of
ourselves when we're thinking about
coding.
Who here's an aspiring Vim user that
like wishes you could use Vim, or even
does?
I know we've all had that Vim phase
where we all tried.
This is just how we are as devs. We care
so deeply about these things. We care so
deeply about our tools, the systems we
pick, the frameworks, the languages.
We like to think it all matters.
And we've blinded ourselves in this. We
think things that just don't make sense
when you take one step back. Like, why
can't we commit our environment files?
It sounds stupid when I put it on a
slide like this, but I want you to
really think about this for a second.
When I have a team of engineers that are
working on a project, why do I have to
build another system to share this
specific file, but all the other files
can go and get just fine?
It's dumb. It's just how Git was built
because it was built for a very specific
thing, and then it took over our
industry, and it took over our brains,
and we aren't letting go of that.
There's a lot of these things in our
heads that we have to start fighting. We
have to take the step back and think,
is this how we do things cuz it's right,
or is this how we do things cuz it's
just how we've always done it?
And as you start to think more about
this, you'll realize there are so many
things that we do this with.
Like, why do we qualify ourselves by the
languages we know?
I used to think this was a junior thing.
Like, I could can't tell you how many
times I had a junior engineer I was
talking to who was like, "Oh, you're a
coder? What languages do you write? I
write JavaScript."
I thought this was a junior problem, but
then you talk to senior engineers who
are like, "Oh, he writes JavaScript.
He's not a real developer."
We care too much. We pride ourselves in
these things. They're our identity.
These weird facts, these weird choices,
these things that feel essential
just don't matter that much anymore. And
they didn't then, and they matter less
now. We got away with it because it was
so hard to find engineers that we could
just tell the company what we were
doing, and they couldn't really say no
cuz the alternative is spend 6 months
trying to hire someone else. They're not
going to do that.
And along that note,
why are we so scared of deleting code? I
cannot tell you how many times I've been
in a conversation with someone
where the solution is to just delete it
and reset, but we have such a bad sunk
cost mindset in this industry. We care
so much about the code we wrote, and we
care so much about it still being there
that I feel bad working with my team
sometimes when somebody files a PR that
isn't quite the right solution, but they
spent a week or two on it. Like, who
here has guilt merged a PR before? Where
you just felt bad because somebody put a
lot of work in, it's not quite the right
thing, but you merge it anyways cuz the
alternative was a conversation you
didn't want to have.
Why do we do this to ourselves? One of
the nice things about ages you don't
have to feel bad when you shut down
their work,
but we we just care too much. It's the
point I'm trying to make. And the things
we care about are not necessarily the
things that matter anymore, and I hope
we can finally start to challenge some
of these.
Going to get a little more personal here
by showing some of the ideas I've built
cuz the goal here is that when you guys
go out of this talk,
you have a better mindset for coming up
with ideas that make sense now by
rejecting the things that made sense
before.
These are three of the things that I
have built or are currently working on.
We're going to go from the bottom up.
I built a Reddit scraper because making
good memes is hard and I would rather
just steal them from Reddit and went
pretty well. It was a side project. It
would take me two to three days. Would
just scrape Reddit, top posts on
programming humor,
put them in a nice format for me so I
could go copy paste them onto Twitter.
Zoom for streamers was a startup I went
through Y Combinator with. It was called
Ping. I wanted to make it easier for
live content creators to do high-quality
collaborations in the software they
already used, OBS.
The full stack cloud is
let's just imagine Vercel, but it goes
further each direction. They have off
built in, but they also have databases
built in. These are all things I've
wanted that I benefit from existing,
enough so that I tried to build all of
them.
The bottom two I built in 2021. The top
one I'm working on right now.
These are also kind of tiers, different
levels that we can build at. If I was to
try and categorize them, I would call
the bottom one side project, call the
middle one startup, and call the top one
too big. It just doesn't make sense.
Well, this is how I would have
categorized this even just a year ago.
But things have changed.
Now that the models are bigger,
the tiers have shifted.
Everything is now one tier lower.
And this is a crazy thing for me to
process. The fact that what used to be a
startup is now a side project. In fact,
some of the startups I've talked to even
at an event like this,
their whole startup could have arguably
been a side project or this bottom tier,
which there's a weird gap there. What's
that?
It's the G brain tier. It's a markdown
file.
Do you know how many companies are at
this event where their whole product
could just be a markdown file?
It's insane.
>> [applause]
>> And like, okay, seriously though,
the fact that you can now execute
markdown by just piping it to Codex or
Claude is unbelievable and I think most
of us haven't fully appreciated how
insane that is. I had a service that
would triage all of my PRs, have them
all get reviewed with AI and then help
me prioritize. That service is a
markdown file now. I just literally
wrote like, go to these four GitHub
repos, look at all the open PRs, figure
out what the current status of the work
is,
and then help me prioritize it. And then
when you're done, go update the static
HTML file and send it to S3 and give me
the URL. And every morning at 9:00 a.m.
this runs on a cron and around 9:15 to
9:20, my markdown file generates me my
work for the day.
What the hell?
How are we actually here now? I
Try that if you have it, by the way.
You'd be amazed how many of these types
of things can exist that are literally
just a markdown file running on a cron.
But what about Okay, two more things I
want to change about this, though.
First is
the full stack cloud. This is mine.
Don't do it. Like bit coming soon. Very
excited. I wouldn't want to compete with
me on this one. Trust me. It's going to
be really cool.
But there's still something else.
There's a gap here.
And I'm going to be real with you guys.
I don't know what goes in this gap.
I don't know what too big means anymore.
Is it training your own model from
scratch? Is it building your own
operating system? Is it trying to
compete with NPM and Node directly? I
don't know. I don't know what too big is
right now. And that's scary, but it's
also exciting. It means I need to keep
pushing myself to go bigger than makes
sense
in order to find these limits.
But what does that even mean? What does
it mean to think bigger in this
scenario?
I would argue that bigger's probably the
wrong word for most of how I'm thinking
here.
It's time to think wider.
What I mean by this is spectrum and I'm
sorry I have to do a diagram. If you
watch my videos, you understand.
There's breadth and depth to any piece
of software. The breadth is the range of
things that your software covers.
And the depth is the number of features
in a given area.
Let's look at a company like Vercel.
Vercel does not offer all of the
features that AWS does. They never will.
It doesn't make sense.
But Vercel offers deeper But Vercel
offers deeper features in the space
they're in, which is full-stack
front-end leaning servers.
If you're a front-end developer and
you're not using Vercel, you're feeling
some amount of pain because they're just
further ahead with this. So much so that
even the agents prefer it.
And this was kind of how you had to
build your startups. Because if you were
competing with a company like AWS,
you're never going to have all of the
features they have. You're never going
to cover the range that they cover.
It'd make no sense to try because you
don't have the thousands of engineers
they do doing that.
At least you didn't.
But now things have changed.
All of a sudden, that range is viable in
a way that it never was before. I'm not
saying you can build something as
reliable as RDS. I'm saying that you can
build a database platform into your
product in a day or two of work with
enough prompting and enough effort.
And if you build your stuff right, if
you play your cards correctly, and you
think about things the right way,
you'll realize that you can build enough
across a spectrum of things you care
about to enable most users to at least
start trying the thing.
And when they have features they need in
a given vertical that you don't support,
it's not your problem.
As long as you build it right. Because
they can build the features that are
missing themselves.
If you architect your systems and you
architect your products in such a way
that users can do things that they you
never would have guessed.
Like Slack accidentally did this because
Slack is now the platform people run
their agents in half the time, which is
crazy. Slack sucks. It's not a good
product, but it's the right shape for
people to build the features they want
into it through the somewhat functional
Slack bot APIs.
This is all crazy cuz I'm basically
sitting here telling you like it's time
to compete with Slack. It's time to
build your own AWS. It's time to
challenge Salesforce directly.
It sounds stupid, but I'm going to be
real.
If your idea doesn't feel stupid,
it's cuz your idea's not big enough.
That's all I have to say. Thank you so
much, AIE.